<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Danube Documentation - HTTP Authentication</title>
  </properties>

  <head>
  </head>

  <body>
    <section name="Authentication">

      <p>
        It is possible to set security in Danube using JAAS technology. It is done through <a href="api/org/abstracthorizon/danube/http/auth/JAASAuthenticator.html">JAASAuthenticator</a>
        connection handler. This handler performes basic http authentication and uses supplied user name and password supplied with preconfigured login context.
        Login context is supplied through <code>loginContextName</code> attribute. If authentication passed then forward connection handler (possible http context) is called.
      </p>
      <p>
        Here are all attributes of authentication class:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li><code>loginContextName</code> - name of login context to be used</li>
        <li><code>handler</code> - reference to handler which is going to be invoked in case of successful authentication</li>
        <li><code>sessionManager</code> - reference to session manager for subject to be placed under &quot;org.abstracthorizon.danube.http.auth.Subject&quot; attribute.</li>
        <li><code>realm</code> - realm as in http basic authentication</li>
        <li><code>loginContext</code> - reference to the login context to be used. It is automatically set if login context name is supplied.</li>
        <li><code>cacheTimeout</code> - timeout for local authorisation string cache. Cache contains subjects mapped to authorisation strings.</li>
        <li><code>minimumScanPeriod</code> - minimal allowed period for cache to be scanned for timed out subjects</li>
      </ul>

      <p>
        For authentication using JAAS to work appropriate LoginContext must be defined. Login modules must use username/password authentication for it to work.
      </p>

      <p>
        New types of authentications are planned for the future implementations such as public/private SSL key, Acegi, etc...
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
